I was told Amnesia is a horror game,
but to my surprise, it was actually an FPS.
So now I wonderÉ can Amnesia compete with Call of Duty?
Even though it's missing competitive match making.
What does Amnesia mean?
No, I'm actually askingÉ
someone told me, but I forgot.
When I think about the game, I think about the amnesia gold rush back in the 1800's
When a man could go on Youtube, upload one minute of Amnesia footage
and make enough money to buy a horse.
When you start the game the developers will tell you that you are suppose to immerge yourself in the story
and not focus on winning. But they are a bit bias.
And I am a rebelÉ so this is my Amnesia setup.
The game starts with our main character saying his name is Daniel, seven times.
Daniel is suffering from memory deficit, usually caused by psychological trauma or physical damage to the temporal lobeÉ
*sight*É If only there was an easier way of saying that.
Our first quest is to follow this, somewhat, tasty looking pink stuff.
As we follow the liquid, Daniel remembers his first memoryÉ that he's the world limbo champion.
Eventually, we get to this letter from himself.
Daniel, It's meÉ you.
If you are reading this, that means you have lost your memory.
Yes I know, it's the second time it happens.
But at least, this timeÉ we didn't wake up in a police station.
But listen mate. I need you to find Baron AlexanderÉ and kill him. He's in the inner sanctum.
Should probably have killed him before I drank the memory losing drink and you'd wakeÉ
but I didn't think that far.
Also could you check on the stove, I'm like 90% sure I turn it off.
So we have to go to the inner sanctum.
Where is that?
Like Frictional's other game Bioshock, you hear old conversations as you walk around.
and in one of these conversation, you learn that the inner sanctum lies beneath the very stone of the castle.
which is a very fancy way of saying :
Ç It's in the basement. È
ButÉ oh no! the way is blocked by this somewhat tasty looking goo.
What do we do now?
Ho! I know, we should produce industrial acid!
It's the only logical action.
So we go to the laboratory, where we found out that Baron Alexander tried to create artificial life energyÉ
By throwing random things in acid
but he gave up when he realized that chemistry is hard.
And he moved all the chemistry ingredients to the wine cellar.
So he can revolutionize wine
The wine cellar door is locked.
So we have to search for the key in the archives.
Dany, the main character, used to be an archaeologist.
Right now he is uncovering mysteries but he used to uncover dinosaur bones.
We find diary entries from Daniel's archeology trip to Algeria.
There are 3 pages about his findings and 78 about how the airport lost his luggage.
The diary tells the story of him getting trapped in a tomb and finding an mysterious blue orb.
Daniel immediately assumes that the orb is alien.
Yes, he is one of those peoples that ruined History channel.
Yeeaah!É wine cellar key!
Welcome to the wine cellar, as you can see, it is very dark.
That's kind of Amnesia's thing.
There are two ways to get light.
One is through tinderboxes.
Tinderboxes are probably Alexander's greatest obsession. Because the castle has 148 tinderboxes.
Jesus Christ!
I own zero, and I get along just fine.
The other way is the lantern, but it runs on oil.
So I didn't want to use it because I care about the environment.
But I didn't think I would run out of tinderboxesÉ
Work god dammit, WORK!
But I didÉ a lotÉ
So I had to use the lantern.
I guess, Daniel's memory loss made him forget that he can carry candles.
I also guess that he forgot that it's not normal to have telekinetic powers.
If you stand in the dark for too long you loose your sanity.
If you go completely insaneÉ things get, very different.
In the wine cellar we find a bunch of useless items and Ç royal water È acid.
Then we mix the useless stuffs with the Ç royal water È acidÉ to create normal acid.
We have to downgrade so our bucket doesn't melt.
The acid worksÉ yeeaaah!
this is the refinery. Here we have our first encounter with the gatherers.
The iconic villains that makes you go : Ç OhÉ that's it? È
until you actually play the game.
They like to steal living creatures, probably to bring them to Alexander, because he's lonely.
He lives in a castle so big it could be divided into states.
The refinery is very short, you enter this cellar archives, then things go dark and it's full of water.
This is what happen when you buy a massive castle and save money on plumbing.
AndÉ there is a monster in the water that follows you.
Warning!É the following segment has been deemed extremely stressful.
please enjoy the coming sounds of Pachelbel.
DON'T CLOSE, DON'T CLOSE, DON'T CLOSE!
SPIN, SPIN, SPINNILY SPIN
Why would you install this? Seems very impractical.
How do you open doors?
I hate you Frictional.
Of course! there is more water.
Did they build this castle on a lac?
The castle has an elevatorÉ I'm guessing that's where the plumbing money went.
But the elevator is off-line.
First we need the key to the machine room.
AhÉ First person platformingÉ we meet again my old nemesis.
Yeeaah!É machine room key!
The machine room is a two-part puzzle.
The first part is a Math puzzle.
*Hurrr*
The second part is where you collect a bunch of items and put them in the machine.
[Hans] Ç HallŒ Sven, I need your help with an other puzzle. È
[Sven] Ç HansÉ I can't help you nowÉ I'm playing a new MMO. È
[Hans] Ç OOOoooohhhhhhh! È
Why am I doing a fake Swedish accent?
While searching for the parts to the machine we find more diary entries from Daniel.
Apparently he returned to London from Algeria, and, everyone he knows is dying.
He thinks it's because of the blue orb.
Could be something else thoughtÉ there must be hundreds of curses in Algerian tombs.
We fix the machine and now we are in this claustrophobic elevator.
The biggest surprise right now, would be if nothing went wrong.
*arf*É of course
Welcome to the prisonÉ not a dungeon.
In a flashback conversation, Alexander says anyone who calls it a dungeon will be sued for defamation.
To get to the next level, we need to get through this hole, but Daniel is too big.
I never solved this puzzle.
I searched for a solution and kept walkingÉ Eventually Daniel had lost enough weight to get through.
This tunnel is very scary, I bet we are going to meet the grotesque tunnel monster.
And we are out. I guess we are going to explore moreÉ prison.
YippeeÉ
In this part of the game you get lost.
The gatherers are still a bit scary, but they get way less scary when you realize
they have the intelligence of a 6 months old infant.
We find diary entries from Daniel about coming to the castle and showing Alexander the orb.
He says Daniel has gotten a curse from the orb.
But it can be removed for a hefty priceÉ of 400Û
But Daniel can't afford that, because euros hasn't been invented yet.
Finally we stop being lost and enter the cistern.
Ç What is a cistern? È some of you might be wondering.
Well, you see, it's the old Latin word for Burger king.
This part is really disturbingÉ
Daniel will order something, and when the cashier gives you your food, she says : Ç Enjoy your meal. È
And Daniel automatically responds : Ç You too. È
It's the first time Amnesia actually gets scary.
So you quickly run to the back-door and entered the morgue located next to the Burger king.
We need to enter the sewer, but it's filled with mushroom gas.
But there is a vaccine in the morgue.
But instead of looking for it, Daniel has the brilliant idea of injecting himself
with the blood of a recently deceased corpse.
I'm not gonna question it, because it worked!
In the sewers, nothing happens.
You guys wanna know why this game got destroyed by Call of Duty?
And we only got half a sequel instead of a new one every year?
First of all, it's set in PrussiaÉ No one likes Prussia, that's why it doesn't exist anymore.
It should be set in modern day New York.
Replace Daniel and the gatherers
with Navy SEALs and terrorists.
Also the dark descent is a stupid sub-title, I would call it :
Amnesia
Ground Mission DarkÉ Dark Aqua Zero
Daniel climbs out of the sewer.
Welcome to the nave.
Here you meet Agrippa and he's like :
[German Accent] Ç Hallo Daniel, can you create ein tonic for me?
All you need is mushrooms and saliva from the wassermonster.
If you want to know how we came up with this tonicÉ don't ask.
Also, if you want to enter the inner sanctum, you needÉ a second orb.
Find 6 orb pieces und connect them, you should be able to find them next to unique 3D objects È.
We find another entry, and it tells us Alexander explains to Daniel that to delay the curse,
you could torture and kill people.
So Alex brings him prisoners and Daniel does that.
But then likeÉ when you listen to a song, enough time, you start to like it.
Same thing happened to Daniel, but with torture.
So one day Alexander tells him :
[Alexander] Ç Daniel, you have completely lost itÉ
also I'm a supernatural being from an other dimension. Our kind can live forever. Guess how? È
[Daniel] Ç By eating tinderboxes. È
[Alexander] Ç How did you? È
[Daniel] Ç You haveÉ 150 tinderboxes and zero matches È
[Alexander] Ç Screw you! I'm going to return to my own dimension. Suck on my 300 years old balls È
*unzips his fly*
[Daniel] Ç OKÉ I'm going to kill you. But after seeing thatÉ I need the amnesia potion. È
Next to stuffs Daniel has used for torture, we find orb parts.
Then Daniel get captured and put into a cell.
Fortunately, this wall has a self-destruct button.
And the key to this dungeon is in a pipe.
Maybe things are finally going up for old Daniel.
OH SHIT, OH SHIT, OH SHIT!
UhhÉ some more important plot stuff is revealed, but it's not important.
Now we have the tonic! We give it to Agrippa, and he tells us toÉ cut off his head.
Now we have a head.
WaitÉ carrying around a headÉ acid in a bucketÉ a curseÉ historicalÉ
Amnesia is a remake of Monkey Island!
But unlike the original, Amnesia has three endings.
When you enter the inner sanctum, Alexander will say :
UhhÉ Good vs evil, Daniel, doesn't matter because I'm flyingÉ I bet you're really jealous!
To get the Ç bad ending È, don't do anything. Alexander will return to his world, and then Daniel wakes up, and it was all a dream.
That's why it's call the Ç bad ending È, because of bad writing.
To get Ç revenge ending È, you have to destruct the ritual, and then spray Alexander with root beerÉ
This is of course the original ending.
And finally to get the Ç good ending È, you put the head in the portal, then you travel amongst the stars, and the headÉ talks to a guy.
This might be very confusing, and it doesn't help that I stopped explaining the story 5 minutes ago.
I actually don't think I've spoiled a single thing in this entire video.
And that is the Kilian experience.
Like, subscribe, etceteraÉ
The next video, the next garbage review I meanÉ will be the one year anniversary of the channel.
So I'm going to do an obscure game. So recommend obscure games.